Guide to the Dr. Richard Buswell papers 1998-2021
Montana Historical Society
Dr. Richard Buswell papers
1998-2021
Montana Historical Society Archives
MC 391
Buswell, Dr. Richard
1.4 linear feet of shelf space.
This collection consists entirely of correspondence (1998-2018) between Dr. Richard Buswell of Helena, Montana and Lee Silliman of Missoula, Montana. Correspondence is primarily incoming to Buswell, and discusses Silliman’s travels (including to Montana ghost towns) and his photographic methods. Correspondence range from hand-written and typed letters, to e-mails. Additional printed material included in the original mailings have been kept with the correspondence.
Biographical Note
Dr. Richard Buswell was born in Helena, Montana on January 24, 1945 to Howard and Agatha Virginia Arnaud Buswell. He graduated from Helena High School in 1963, publishing some of his early photographs in the Nugget, the Helena High School newspaper. Between 1963 and 1966 he attended Carroll College, graduating magna cum laude with a Bachelor of the Arts degree in Biology. He earned his medical degree from Oregon Health Sciences University in Portland in 1970. A year later he purchased his first camera, a Nikkormat, and began taking photographs of Montana ghost towns, mining camps, and homesteads. In 1974 he married Sue Ann Vinkovich, and the couple would have three children: Erica, Stephanie, and Timothy. Dr. Buswell has presented over thirty solo and group exhibitions across the nation. He has also published several collections of his photographic work, including a book entitled, "Echoes: A Visual Reflection."
Lee Silliman was a high school physics, chemistry, and mathematics instructor for forty-three years. He was also the part-time photo archivist for the Powell County Museum and Arts Foundation in Deer Lodge for twenty-six years. He began his work with photography in 1979, and built his own darkroom in 1983. Silliman has assembled and circulated fifteen different exhibitions that have been displayed in more than ninety institutions throughout Montana and ten other states since 1988.
This collection consists entirely of correspondence (1998-2018) between Dr. Richard Buswell, a Helena physician and photographer, and Lee Silliman, former high school teacher and photographer. Correspondence is primarily incoming to Buswell, and discusses Silliman’s travels (including to Montana ghost towns) and his photographic methods.
Arranged by series and chronologically.
Collection is open for research
Acquisition information available upon request.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Buswell, Dr. Richard
Montana
Documentary photography.; Photographers--Montana; Images, Photographic; Ghost towns--Montana; Homestead Law--Montana--Photographic images
Montana
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Incoming Correspondence
  - Incoming to Richard Buswell from Lee Silliman, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 1 / 1)
  - Incoming to Richard Buswell from Lee Silliman, 2002-2008 (Box-folder 1 / 2)
  - Incoming to Richard Buswell from Lee Silliman, 2008-2009 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
  - Incoming to Richard Buswell from Lee Silliman, 2009-2011 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
  - Incoming to Richard Buswell from Lee Silliman, 2011-2012 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
  - Incoming to Richard Buswell from Lee Silliman, 2012-2013 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
  - Incoming to Richard Buswell from Lee Silliman, 2013-2015 (Box-folder 2 / 1)
  - Incoming to Richard Buswell from Lee Silliman, 2014-2015 (Box-folder 2 / 2)
  - Incoming to Richard Buswell from Lee Silliman, 2016 (Box-folder 2 / 3)
  - Incoming to Richard Buswell from Lee Silliman, 2017 (Box-folder 3 / 1)
  - Incoming to Richard Buswell from Lee Silliman, 2018 (Box-folder 3 / 2)
- Outgoing Correspondence
  - Outgoing to Lee Silliman from Richard Buswell, 2013-2018 (Box-folder 3 / 3)
  - Outgoing e-mails to Lee Silliman from Richard Buswell, 2014-2017 (Box-folder 3 / 4)
- 2020 Donation
  - Biographical
    - Richard S. Buswell M.D. Curriculum Vita & Artist Vita, undated (Box-folder 3 / 5)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - John Ellingsen (re: John's work in Viginia City and Nevada City and his publication The Montanian, 1998-2016 (Box-folder 3 / 6)
  - Incoming/Outgoing Correspondence
    - Lee Silliman, 2015 - 2018 July (Box-folder 3 / 7)
    - Lee Silliman, 2018 August - 2019 August (Box-folder 3 / 8)
- 2022 Donation
  - Incoming/Outgoing Correspondence
    - Lee Silliman, 2019 September - 2020 July (Box-folder 4 / 1)
    - Lee Silliman, 2020 August - 2021 May (Box-folder 4 / 2)
    - Lee Silliman, 2021 June - 2021 September (Box-folder 4 / 3)
    - Lee Silliman, 2021 October - 2021 December (Box-folder 4 / 4)
  - Photos
    - Evans Ranch + Fergus County MT, 2017 (Box-folder 4 / 5)
  - Clippings
    - Newspaper Clippings, 2020 (Box-folder 4 / 6)